A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739E
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Africa on the information highway: putting scientific and scholarly information in the hands and computers of African researchers (Reports 012877-022), 1995 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  A paper delivered at a seminar: Archives as Cultural Documentation Places and Cultural Links Connecting Peoples, Associacao de Professores e Investigadores de Lingua Portuguesa (July 24-28, 1995: Arrabida, Portugal);Accompanied by table of contents to: S
  Academic libraries -- Africa; Library science -- Africa; Information superhighway -- Africa; Education, Higher -- Africa -- Computer networks; American Association for the Advancement of Science. Project for African Research Libraries
- The emerging role of African universities in the development of science and technology, 1994 Excerpt (Reports 012877-023) (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  Excerpt on distance learning and programmed instruction in science and engineering in Africa from an AAU study, examining obstacles and prospects.
  Distance education -- Africa; Programmed instruction -- Africa; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Africa; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Africa; Association of African Universities
- Strategic development plans to enhance the contribution of women to universities in Southern Africa: report for the Association of Commonwealth Universities, Dec. (Reports 012877-024), 1994 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  Drawing on previous seminars and management training courses organized by the Association of Commonwealth Universities, the author traces developments and calls for strategic needs analyses, development plans and proposals for funding to support the contr
  Women college admnistrators -- Training of -- Africa, Southern; Women scholars -- Africa; Women in education -- Africa, Southern; Universities and colleges -- Africa, Southern; Association of Commonwealth Universities
- Issues concerning postgraduate education in South Africa: report to the Ford Foundation, June 1 (Reports 012877-025), 1994 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  "This report is based upon discussions conducted in South Africa during the period of April 29 to May 13, including meetings with administrators and faculty at nine universities. It is meant to assist the Ford Foundation in considering its role vis-a-vis
  Education, Higher -- South Africa; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- South Africa; Ford Foundation. Africa and Middle East Regional Program
- Welcome books: Board of trustees overseas meetings: Windhoek (Reports 012878-001), 1996 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  Schedules, itineraries and lists of participants at the March 1996 Trustees' meeting in South Africa.
  Trustee Briefing books;March 1996
- Welcome books: Board of trustees overseas meetings -- Maputo (Reports 012878-002), 1996
- Welcome books: Board of trustees overseas meetings -- Durban (Reports 012878-003), 1996
- Welcome books: Board of trustees overseas meetings -- Johannesburg (Reports 012878-004), 1996
- Welcome books: Board of trustees overseas meetings -- Capetown March 30 -April 2 (Reports 012878-005), 1996
- Evaluation of the organization for development and support of street food vendors in the city of Minia: model for empowering the working poor (Reports 012879), 1993 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  Model for empowering the working poor. --T.p.
  Street vendors -- Egypt; Vending stands -- Law and legislation -- Egypt; Social planning -- Egypt; Social Planning, Analysis, & Administration Consultants; Ford Foundation. Governance and Public Policy
- Rapporteur's notes on a Funders' meeting on Welfare Reform and Reproductive Health, April 10 (Reports 012880), 1997 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  Governance and Public Policy/Reproductive Health and Population
  Public welfare -- United States; Reproductive health -- United States; Ford Foundation. Governance and Public Policy; Ford Foundation. Reproductive Health and Population
- Testing assumptions: a survey of teachers' attitudes towards the nation's school reform agenda (Reports 012881), 1993 (Box 651, Reel R-9285)
  Educational change; Educational surveys; Teachers -- Attitudes; LH Research
- Briefing book: Trustee Committee site visit Eastern Shore of Virginia, March 25-26 (Reports 012883), 1997 (Box 899, Reel R-9285)
  "This is one of the most exciting things ever to happen in the field of conservation...People all over the country tell us they've been inspired by what folks are doing on the Virginia Eastern Shore (p. 3, Economy or Environment, by Christopher Reardon).
  Board of Trustees;Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Community and Resource Development
  09101210;09401004;09700320;09501539;09501474;95P-3003
  [Trustee Briefing books, March 1997]
  Environmental protection -- Eastern Shore (Md. and Va.); Community development -- Eastern Shore (Md. and Va.); Ford Foundation. Board of Trustees; Ford Foundation. Conservation-Based Community Development Initiative; Nature Conservancy (U.S.)
- The Ford Foundation Corporate Involvement Initiative: Partner convening, Sepember 29-30 (Reports 012884), 1997 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  "The goal of the Corporate Involvement Initiative is to increase substantially the involvement of corporations in community and economic development (CED)..." The Agenda of the meeting sets forth three goals: 1. Learn about each other's work, including th
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Education
  09701629;09751739
  The Conference Board, Inc.
  Community development -- Training -- United States -- Congresses; Corporations -- United States -- Congresses; Social responsibility of business -- United States -- Congresses; Nonprofit organizations -- Congresses; Ford Foundation. Corporate Involvement Initiative; Ford Foundation. Corporate Involvement Initiative
- Natural Resources Management Program Officer Consultation, Napa Valley, California, June 9-11 (Reports 012885), 1996 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Documents from a gathering of the Environment and Development Affinity Group (EDAG), with memos, essays and staff biographies.
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Community and Resource Development
  various pagings: ill.;28 cm.
  Conservation of natural resources; Community development -- Environmental aspects; Land use; Sustainable development; Ford Foundation. Environment and Development Affinity Group
- African studies at the millennium: a review of Ford Foundation African studies grantees, 1995-1997, Aug. 6 (Reports 012886) (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Focuses on 7 key issues: 1) "The relations between North American African studies programs ... and institutions and scholars based in Africa;2) The limited diversity in African Studies and the infrequency of solid and enduring linkages with the African Am
  African studies grants -- Evaluation; Grantees -- African American scholars; Grantees -- African scholars
- Report to the Ford Foundation: a review of selected endowment grants, Apr. (Reports 012887), 1991 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  "Beginning in 1982, the Foundation awarded a substantial number of endowment grants to long time grantees. The factors that led to these grants included: a desire on Ford's part to provide continued yearly support to the grantees in a way that would enhan
  Program Division
- Review of the Minority Opportunities Through School Transformation Program - (MOST II), administered by the Minority Affairs Program (MAP) Office, American Sociological Association (ASA), Feb. (Reports 012888), 1998 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  "The MOST program review was designed to consider four variables: (1) unique programs or activity in participating departments;(2) institutional type (undergraduate or graduate institution);(3) region of the country (i.e., North, South, East or West);(4)
  Educational equalization -- United States; Minority Opportunities Through School Transformation Program
- The greater vision: Social science in the service of general education, Nov. (Reports 012889), 1992 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  "The goal of the 1987 Ford Foundation Initiative in Social Science Undergraduate Education was to improve the quality of undergraduate education by bringing to students the methods, perspectives and knowledge of the social sciences as these inform our und
  Social sciences -- Study and teaching (Higher); Ford Foundation. Initiative in Social Science Undergraduate Education
- Assets, sexuality and reproductive health (Reports 012890), 1998 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Documents from a worldwide gathering of the Reproductive Health Affinity Group, with memos, background reading, staff biographies, including Seminar on men, family formation and reproduction (Buenos Aires, 13-15 May, 1998), and The asset vulnerability fra
  Human Development and Reproductive Health
  09890018
  Women -- Health and hygiene; AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention; Sexually transmitted diseases -- Prevention; Birth control; Sex instruction for teenagers; Ford Foundation. Reproductive Health Affinity Group
- Reproductive health review meeting, Bohol, Philippines, August 6-8 (Reports 012891), 1997 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  09790016
  Support for consultations to enhance the Foundation's role in advancing the field of reproductive health.
  Reproductive health review meeting (Aug. 6-8, 1997: Bohol, Philippines)
  Reproductive health review meeting; Reproductive health -- Philippines -- Congresses; Birth control -- Philippines -- Congresses; Women -- Health and hygiene -- Philippines; Public health -- Philippines; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Southeast Asia; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- A study of Nigeria's national initiative in developing a local level primary health care program: the impact of community participation on coverage of primary health care services, integration of care, and client satisfaction in Nigeria, Dec. (Reports 012892), 1987 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  08651016
  University of Lagos
  Public health -- Nigeria; Medical care -- Nigeria; University of Lagos
- Board Meeting papers (Reports 012893), 1996 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Includes plans for meeting for PSJ, EMAC, and ABCD and discussion paper "The Ford Foundation's program in Mexico and Central America."[…]"In connection with the December 1996 Board of Trustees Meeting, enclosed is one set of the following: [1] Program overview and related materials for each of the three program areas (Asset Building and Community Development, Education, Media, Arts and Cu
  [Trustee meeting papers, Dec. 1996]
- Papers from Program Committee meetings (Reports 012894), 1996 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Materials presented for discussion at Program Committee meetings for ABCD, EMAC and PSJ held on September 25, 1996.
  [Program committee meeting papers, Sept. 25, 1996]
  Human rights; Social justice; Community development; Charity organization; Ford Foundation Program development
- A history of the Ford Foundation's work on police issues (Reports 012895), 1997 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Surveys domestic and foreign initiatives in police work, notably the Police Foundation, extensively citing RGA #08700987, which supported its permanent endowment and heralded a tie- off for domestic programs. As of the late 1990s, interest persists in pol
  08700987
  History of the Ford Foundations work on police issues
  Police -- Training of; Police administration; Criminal justice, Administration of; Community policing; Police Foundation (U.S.)
- Community economic development assessment: A national study of urban community development corporations, preliminary findings, Jun. (Reports 012896), 1989 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  The Community Economic Development Assessment (CEDA) began in 1986 as an effort to capture basic descriptive information about community development corporations (CDCs). Key questions in the minds of those conceptualizing the work included: what do these,NULL,NULL,NULL,NULL,NULL,Access may be restricted; consult Archivist.,NULL
  Community development corporations -- United States -- Evaluation; Community Economic Development Assessment
- Directory of U.S. Foundations with grant programs in Asia (Reports 012897), 1990 (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  Philanthropy -- Asia -- Directories
- The Ford Foundation Reproductive Health and Population Program meeting notes, April 27-30, 1993, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Reports 012898) (Box 652, Reel R-9285)
  "The purpose of this particular meeting was to 1) reinforce the common framework that underlies the individual field offices' work, and 2) as the program seeks to bring new perspectives and approaches to the field, to exchange information, experiences and
  Reproductive Health and Population
  Ethics and reproductive health
  Sexuality; Birth control; AIDS (Disease); Abortion; Ford Foundation. Reproductive Health and Population
- Report to the Ford Foundation on nine legal grantees of the Refugee and Migrant Rights and Policy Portfolio, Nov. 24 (Reports 012899), 1998 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  Human Rights and International Cooperation
  09891007
  Legal assistance to refugees; Legal assistance to immigrants; Ford Foundation. Human Rights and International Cooperation
- Sociology and Anthropology in China (Reports 012900), 1990 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  Accompanied by directories: Sociologists and anthropologists in the U.S.;North American Chinese sociologists, 1988-1989 directory (includes names in Chinese);excerpt from: Research centers directory (14th ed., 1990), and: Brief report to the Lingnan Found
  China
  Brief report to the Lingnan Foundation;North American Chinese sociologists;Sociologists and anthropologists in the U.S.
  Sociology -- China -- Study and teaching; Anthropology -- China -- Study and teaching; Sociologists -- China -- Directories; Anthropologists -- China -- Directories; China -- Social conditions -- Study and teaching -- Bibliography
- Uplands development in Vietnam: report of an exploratory survey to determine World Neighbors' potential role in uplands development in Vietnam, Oct. (Reports 012901), 1992 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  Rural development -- Vietnam; World Neighbors (Organization)
- Narrative report to the Ford Foundation on language-linked approaches to mathematics instruction, 1987-1988, Feb. (Reports 012902), 1989 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  Describes the evolution of an experimental course at NYU for incoming Freshmen into a remedial program forming part of New York State's Stay in School Partnership Program (SSPP) for Bushwick, Sarah J. Hale and Prospect Heights High Schools in Brooklyn, an
  Education and Culture; Urban Poverty program
  08600865
  New York University
  Language linked approaches to mathematics instruction
  Mathematics -- Remedial teaching; English -- Remedial teaching; New York University. School of Education; Stay in School Partnership Program; New York University
- The Ford Foundation Program in the Andean Region and Southern Cone (Reports 012903), 1998 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  Focuses on political and social developments in Argentina, Chile, Colombia and Peru, notably the tenuous transition to democracy, reviewing past activities and outlining benchmarks for future FF programming.[…]For discussion at the September 1998 meeting of the Board of Trustees. --T.p.
  Trustee Meeting papers;September 1998
  Technical assistance -- Andes Region; Technical assistance -- Southern Cone of South America; Technical assistance -- Latin America; Endowments -- Andes Region -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Southern Cone of South America -- Evaluation; Endowments; Ford Foundation. Andean Region and Southern Cone
- Report to the Ford Foundation on a visit to Vietnam to assess research and training in international relations, March 21-28 (Reports 012904), 1992 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  Professors Kahler and Leifer journeyed to Hanoi in March 1992 "with the object of assessing the state of research and training in International Relations and of suggesting ways in which these two activities might be improved." Their assessment focuses on
  International relations -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Vietnam
- A resource directory of Asian and Pacific Islander HIV/AIDS groups in the United States (Reports 012905), 1993 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  "This directory of Asian and Pacific Islander HIV/AIDS groups was developed to serve as a resource for the Foundation's grantees in Asia and the Pacific Islands...Furthermore, since most HIV/AIDS groups in the U.S. have more access to information than man
  AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention; AIDS (Disease) -- Patients -- Services for -- Directories; Pacific Islanders -- Services for -- Directories; Asians -- Services for -- Directories
- Empowerment through non-violence: voices of Tibetan women in exile (Reports 012906), 1993 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  The author surveys the situation in Tibet and interviews six women, including Rinchen Khando-la, President of the Tibetan Women's Association or TWA (also commonly known by its Tibetan name: Bod kyi bud med lhan tshogs, in Dharamsala, India). As the autho
  Empowerment through nonviolence, voices of Tibetan women in exile
  Women's rights -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region (China); Torture -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region (China); Buddhist nuns -- Crimes against -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region (China); Human rights -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region (China); Bod-kyi Bud-med Lhan-tshogs (Dharmsāla, India)
- Dateline Hanoi: now what? (Reports 012907), 1994 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  International relations -- Vietnam -- Study and teaching (Higher)
- Indian economic research institutions: some implications of India's recent structural adjustment, Aug. (Reports 012908), 1992 (Box 653, Reel R-9285)
  The government of India (GOI) has recently instituted a series of radical economic reforms aimed at the liberalization and globalization of its markets...Major questions are raised about the process and nature of the liberalization...and the ways in whic,NULL,NULL,NULL,NULL,NULL,Access may be restricted; consult Archivist.,NULL
  Economic research -- India; Research institutes -- India -- Directories
- Access to property and its relationship to sex ratios in India, Oct. (Reports 012909), 1990 (Box 654, Reel R-9285)
  Right of property -- India; Women's rights -- India
- East Europe trip, February 3-8 (Reports 012910), 1997 (Box 654, Reel R-9285)
  Includes reviews of grantees: Stefan Batory Foundation, Institute of Public Affairs, European Foundation Center (EFC), and the Polish Committee of NGOs, as well as reprints: Toward 21st Century, Part II, the operation of the Stefan Batory Foundation, and
  09200735;09400748;09500716;09550880
  Stefan Batory Foundation;Helsinki Foundation for Human Rights
  Human rights -- Europe, Eastern; Public interest law -- Europe, Eastern; Technical assistance -- Europe, Eastern; Endowments -- Europe, Eastern -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. International Affairs; Fundacja im. Stefana Batorego; International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights
- International human rights law: its application in national jurisprudence (Reports 012911), 1992 (Box 654, Reel R-9285)
  Human rights -- Legal aspects; Refugees -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Human rights advocacy; Aspen Institute. Seminar for Judges
- Community Development Venture Capital Alliance: meeting, Dec. 5-6 (Reports 012912), 1995 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Community development -- Finance; Community Development Venture Capital Alliance
- The Ford Foundation Overseas Program Review and meeting of the Board of Trustees (Reports 012913), 1993 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Meeting notes from meeting of the Board of Trustees in Prague, Czech Republic, September 30-October 1, 1993.
  Board of Trustees;Rights and Social Justice
  [Trustee Meeting papers, Sept. 30-Oct. 2, 1993]
  Human rights -- Congresses; Social justice -- Congresses; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice
- Ford Foundation Rights and Social Justice program meeting Cape Town, South Africa, May 23-27 (Reports 012914), 1993 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Includes site visit profiles and background readings.
  Philanthropy -- Worldwide; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice
- Ford Foundation program review and Board of Trustees meeting, Moscow (Reports 012915), 1993 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Photographs and biographies of Board members.
  Office of the Secretary;Board of Trustees
  [Trustee Meeting papers, Sept. 26-Oct. 2, 1993]
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Board of Trustees
- Understanding our rights: a review of the public legal education work of human rights NGOs in Kenya, Nov. (Reports 012916), 1996 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  "This report details a review of the public legal education work of human rights NGOs in Kenya. Through a process of meetings, workshops and interviews held with key organisations ... important information was gathered about the functioning of these organ
  ESA
  Human rights advocacy -- Kenya; Non-governmental organizations -- Kenya; Frontier Consulting
- The Ford Foundation Overseas Program Review and meeting of the Board of Trustees (Reports 012917), 1993 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Schedule of events from Board of Trustees' meeting in Moscow, Russia, September 26-30, 1993.
  Board of Trustees;Developing Countries Program
  [Trustee Meeting papers, September 26-30, 1993.]
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration; Ford Foundation. Developing Countries
- Memos on the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, May-Aug. (Reports 012919), 1989 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Initial discussion of program efforts focuses on: Economic Reform and Management - Environment - and Governance and Human Rights. Memos from the following FF members: Susan V. Berresford, Susan V. Margo Picken, Norman R. Collins, Peter W. Stanley, Enid C
  Environmental protection -- Europe, Eastern; Human rights advocacy -- Europe, Eastern; Philanthropy -- Soviet Union; Philanthropy -- Europe, Eastern; Program development -- Soviet Union; Program development -- Europe, Eastern; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- The Ford Foundation: buildings and gardens, Lodi Estate, New Delhi 1992. (Reports 012920) (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  Pictorial display of the Lodi Estate with floor plans and historical commentary.
  Developing Countries Program;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Buildings; Ford Foundation. Lodi Estate (New Delhi); Ford Foundation India
- Assessment of Slovakia's third sector by the Foundation for a Civil Society through its NGO Development Initiative program, which is made possible by funding from the Ford and Charles Stewart Mott Foundations, Jan. 20- Apr. 20 (Reports 012921), 1997 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  A 3-month study of 203 NGOs in Slovakia comprising democracy and human rights organizations (34%), social service restructuring organizations (44%), economic development organizations (13%) and environmental organizations (9%) found a shortage of advocacy
  Peace and Social Justice/Governance and Civil Society
  09700166
  The Foundation for A Civil Society, Ltd.
  Non-governmental organizations -- Slovakia; Civil society -- Slovakia; Foundation for a Civil Society. NGO Development Initiative; Ford Foundation; Charles Stewart Mott Foundation; The Foundation for A Civil Society, Ltd.
- The role of community development financial institutions in Poland: Report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 012922), 1996 (Box 655, Reel R-9285)
  A review of community development financial institutions (CDFIs) in Poland undertaken by Thomas Dichter, Milam Fitts, Mary Houghton and Ron Grzywinski of Shorebank Corporation.